<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Lives Are Not Our Own</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I heard an interesting quote the other day. A quote I had heard before but never really given that much thought until now. It’s a quote from the movie Cloud Atlas. “Our lives are not our own.” I’ve seen Cloud Atlas a couple of times, and I think I have convinced myself that I like that movie. Apart from being horribly difficult to follow the storyline, I find the vagueness and uncertainty of its plot refreshing. Now if you have seen Cloud Atlas, there is a very good chance you thoroughly hated it. For obvious reasons I won’t get into in depth, it is a movie that demands a cult following but nothing more. So as I would quote this line in different conversations, somewhat ironically, I found myself stumbling about what it would look like to embody this group of words (which in all likelihood were probably thrown together for the sole purpose of confusing people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our lives are not our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it look like for someone to live a life for something other than themselves. Initially, I thought wholesome things would pop into my head. Words like selflessness, stewardship seemed like obvious choices. But when I really tried to picture someone living out this idea, the scene quickly darkened. I pictured drug addicts desperately seeking to maintain a lifestyle that hinged upon being dependent on a chemical. Prostitutes conceding their bodies to be dispensable to the next Smoe to walk up to them. Terrorist murderers who in their minds are heroes to be praised on behalf of some junk god that doesn’t exist. Boy….that escalated quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that we as individuals can devote our lives to literally anything, whether it be another person or some bigger cause. I think people tend to devote themselves to other things for many different reasons. For some it may result from a sense of personal inadequacy, a wanting of fulfillment, or a desire to be part of something more significant than they can muster on their own. On the other side, we can ignore this idea and live our lives completely for ourselves. Many people may consider this to ultimately yield a life that is more enjoyable. Personally, I think that is bush-league. Realizing my life is not my own forces me to see in a perspective other than my horribly nearsighted one. It allows me to devote my work to something that will break from the proximity of my personal bubble. But then I begin to wonder…as I look at the devastation that is caused by people who are devoting their lives to things other than themselves but are still trash, maybe it would be better if they just lived a bush-league life and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Our-Lives-Are-Not-Our-Own/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Our-Lives-Are-Not-Our-Own/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mr. Dymaxion</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-ii&quot;&gt;Day II&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah…, I’m definitely more tired than yesterday. Last night was a little difficult but nowhere near a caving point. My two o’clock morning nap was pretty bush-league, which left me waiting six hours to try again. I kept myself pretty preoccupied with some light HTML editing, reading, and watching some shows. However, my 8 o’clock morning went great. I doubt that I hit REM but I fell asleep quickly and awoke feeling very refreshed. I also have been drinking this bottled tea that is so viscous it moves around like syrup. It is hard to tell how much that is contributing to my uppity mood but I am not going to complain about. I have plenty more tea if that’s what Dymaxion Josh needs to operate. Mentally, I feel that I am still operating near capacity. Not knowing how to test this, I went ahead and jotted down a couple of the throughts bouncing around my head. Everything seems to check out…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemons shouldn’t have any sugar. They’re too freaking sour.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All roads should be paved with bricks.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cracking eggs with one hand is fun.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ronald McDonald is a creep.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Poly-What-Day-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Poly-What-Day-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mr. Dymaxion - Day I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;And then came….day one. Out of context, this fragment is probably meaningless to most, but a crazy person will immediately recognize this as a reference to the birth of a brand new polyphasic sleeper. Yes, it is true, I am embarking on a quest to adapt my body to function on a polyphasic sleep cycle instead of the more socially acceptable monophasic sleep cycle. What is a polyphasic sleep schedule you may ask? That is a great question. I will now begin to answer it with a whole bunch of near-factual information. This information will be regurgitate from the readings of Wikipedia articles and forum posts which means that there is something to learn by reading it but there is no guarantee that any of it is true.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Picture a crying newborn baby. It is constantly waking up its mother and father. You might think that the baby is doing this because the baby wants to make its parents’ lives genuinely horrible. This could be true especially if you consider the &lt;del&gt;documentary&lt;/del&gt; movie “Superbabies: Baby Geniuses” but it may also be the result of the baby having a different sleep schedule than its parents. Newborn babies naturally sleep in two large chunks throughout a 24-hour period. However, over time, babies are trained to be accustomed to sleep a single large chunk of time throughout the normal day, a monophasic cycle. Any sleep schedule that incorporates multiple blocks of sleep throughout a 24-hour period is called a polyphasic sleep cycle. There is no research to back the necessity or the benefits of a monophasic sleep cycle over polyphasic sleep cycles. As you will see shortly, the benefits of adopting a polyphasic sleep cycle not hard to uncover.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are a crapton of different types of polyphasic sleep cycles. I will not list all of them and their differences here but will instead focus on the polyphasic cycle that I plan to adopt, the Dymaxion. The Dymaxion is the granddaddy of polyphasic sleep cycles incorporating the least number of naps and the greatest time awake of any of the major polyphasic cycles. Because of the eliteness that the Dymaxion cycle demands, naturally I figured that is where I belong. Specifically, the Dymaxion sleep cycle involves taking four 30-minute naps spaced evenly throughout the day. This results in a total of two hours spent asleep and an astounding twenty-two hours awake.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As you might be able to guess, an “adaptation period” is needed to be able to fully adjust to this new sleep cycle. This adaptation period is said to last about seven to ten days and is filled with crippling sleep deprivation that sends you into a zombie-like trance until your body finally accepts the new sleep cycle. After the adaptation period, users of the Dymaxion report near one hundred percent functioning as if they were sleeping a full eight hours a night. The quick, incomplete explanation of why your body can adapt to extreme sleep cycles such as the Dymaxion goes as follows. REM sleep is super important. The other (deeper) phases of sleep are bushleague. Monophasic sleep cycles are inefficient when it comes to achieving REM sleep (you must track from the lighter levels of sleep to the deeper ones and then back up to hit REM). Once you get over the shock of the new sleep cycles and effectively go through the adaptation period, your body will be trained to immediately enter REM sleep whenever you nap. This allows for a near perfect return of REM sleep during the naps. This effectively makes all time spent asleep, time spent in REM. And bingo, your superman.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So back to day one. This is the first day on the Dymaxion and I feel great! Not super surprising since it is only the first day and I have no real reason to be tired. Coincidently, this is also the first day of classes for spring semester. I figured this was a good of time as any to try out polyphasic sleep for a few reasons. For one, the Dymaxion would not play too nice with a full-time work schedule since the naps need to be taken every six hours. Secondly, I normally don’t get enough sleep as it is when I am in classes usually averaging six hours or so a night. A polyphasic sleep cycle will give me extra time for schoolwork that I never have enough time for and also hopefully keeping me better rested in the long term. Lastly, the first week of classes usually is not too critical. Therefore walking around all zombie-like for a few days should be less of an issue since most professors should be going over syllabuses and reviewing past material for the first week.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have also decided on my personal timing of the four 30-minute naps that I will take throughout the day (and night). I will take them at both two o’clocks and both eight o’clocks. Today, I attempted to nap at these times but failed to fall asleep. I am sure this will be less of problem as the awake hours stretch on further. I’m hoping I’ll be able to really start utilizing these naps tomorrow so I’ll be able to make the transition less painful by allowing myself to reenergize in those thirty minutes without becoming completely sleep deprived. I suspect that this will be difficult due to my crappy ability to fall asleep in a reasonable amount of time combined with my sub-par napping ability. This might get interesting…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Poly-What-Day-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Poly-What-Day-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Frank J. Bricardo.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Frank J. Bricardo violently awakes in a cold sweat. He instinctively spins his head left and right but sees nothing. He sees nothing because it is horribly, horribly dark. This is not the kind of darkness you fall asleep to, the kind that wraps you in a chilled blanket as you drift off asleep. No, this is real darkness. Darkness that suffocates not only your eyes but your ears and every inch of your exposed skin. Some may even call it MIDNIGHT. Franky doesn’t usually mind the dark. He has always been somewhat of a self-proclaimed lone wolf and the darkness has always been convenient to that persona, but he can’t stand the MIDNIGHT. He hopelessly continues looking through the dark…but still sees nothing. As he sits, he feels something cool and soft underneath his hands. It feels like sand. It is not sand. After Frank makes it out the cave, which really wasn’t as much a cave as it was an idea, he is overcome by an eerie feeling that his ordeal is not quite over. Just as he is thinking this, he hears a whooshing noise behind him getting closer and closer. As he is trying to put a face to this vaguely familiar sound, his mind flashbacks to a time much more simple. Flash back. Little boy Franky feels the breeze against his hair as it creeps from the edges of his baseball cap. As he rests his bat on his left shoulder, he readies himself for what is about to come. It is the end of the fourth inning. If he strikeouts, his team will still be ahead by half a dozen points. Him batting right now is thoroughly insignificant at this point. Nevertheless, the pitch is thrown and he moves his bat toward the ball at a “just okay” speed. Flash forward. The whooshing sound. Franky now realizes that the whooshing sound currently approaching the back of his head is the sound of a baseball bat traveling through the air. As an immense panic begins to overtake him, Franky feels a strange calm. When people are met with unimaginable trouble, they often find a surprising peace immediately before the apex of disaster. This is an interesting occurrence as it makes it appear that people are resilient to acceptance of tragedy until the acceptance of such a thing is no longer helpful. For if they would have considered the impending disaster earlier on, it may have been able to be avoided altogether. But people are stubborn, so that’s unrealistic. The phenomenon that I am describing here is not what happened to Franky. Franky did not find peace in the very moments before the baseball bat struck him because he had accepted the gruesome fate that awaited him. No, Franky felt calm because he realized that there was something off with the whooshing sound. The bat carried more of a “thud” than the “ting” as it moved through the air. As Franky realized, the fullness of the noise was the difference of a plastic wiffle ball bat being swung through the air and not a metal baseball bat. The wiffle ball bat strikes Franky squarely in the back of the head making a distinct “ping” sound. Confused and slightly annoyed but unharmed, Franky turns his head to see his attacker/jokester. And just as he does, Franky hears another whooshing sound. This one does have a “ting”. It is moving quicker than the last swing. The hardened aluminum bat lands on Franky’s right temple. No “ping” sound is made. Frank J. Bricardo goes down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Frank-J-Bricardo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Frank-J-Bricardo/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>French Toast!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;French toast. There really isn’t anything quite like it. Who would’ve thought to dunk a piece of toast in some egg and a mess of cinnamon. Beats me… But really, I’m trying to think of something else similarly unusually but I’m completely blanking. There is something special about French toast. I’m just not quite sure what it is yet. I’m more of a pancakes guy myself. Although Belgium waffles are nice for hiding a stupid amount of fruit toppings, powdered sugar, syrup within its crevasses, you just have so much freedom in the outcome of a pancake’s shape and texture. Wait. Belgium waffles. French toast and Belgium waffles. It seems weird that only two out of the three breakfast-carb-trifecta names are preceded by some random European nation. Maybe we should be calling pancakes “Luxemburg delights”. Wow, that sounds way tastier than something that has caked itself to the bottom of some pan. But back to business. Let us take a step back…and then immediately dive head first into the great mystery of this toast from France. (Disclaimer: Any factual information about French toast will not follow. Only pure, unadulterated Josh talk. I look forward to taking this journey with you.)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/French-Toast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/French-Toast/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>